Red lip classic thing that you like
And when we go crashing down
We never go out of style
Ugh.
Help!
So, I understand that you all were
part of the 58th Rescue Squadron...
...staged over at Bagram in Afghanistan
for combat search and rescue.
Yes, ma'am. Two tours.
And you're still flying together?
We all got tight over there.
Wouldn't wanna break up the family.
Dude, do we look like family?
A little.
So, what's the biggest difference between
rescuing over there and what you do here?
Not getting shot at.
- You're a funny guy.
- Yeah.
Uh, Chief Gaines?
I'm told that between
Afghanistan and LAFD...
...you have over 600
documented rescues.
That's pretty impressive.
Just doing my job, ma'am.
Go where they tell me to go.
Heh. That's great. You can cut there.
There she is.
Looks pretty tight.
Take her up.
Winds are variable,
270 to 300. 10 knots gusting to 15.
Metro, this is LAFD.
Helo 5 on scene of cliff-V rescue.
We have visual.
- Copy, Helo 5.
- What's the girl's name?
Natalie.
Metro, connect her cell
to our sat phone.
Helo 5, you're connected.
Hello?
This is Chief Pilot Raymond Gaines
of the Los Angeles Fire Department.
I'm piloting the chopper above you.
You holding up all right?
I don't know. I'm not feeling very well.
Oh, my God! The car is sliding.
Natalie, I'm gonna need you
to stay calm, honey.
- We're coming to get you, okay?
- Okay.
Seven miles visibility...
...winds are 270 at 10 knots.
We show you
one plus one five playtime.
Man, I don't see a way in.
We're gonna tip the hat.
- Tip the hat?
- Yeah.
You might wanna hold on to something.
Here we go.
Fifteen feet out.
Ten feet.
Five.
Whoa, whoa. Easy, Ray.
All right, you got it.
All right.
Tuck them in, boys.
Joby, forget the basket.
We gotta do a double tie-in
on this one.
That car goes, so does she.
Door's open.
Get this.
Hooking up.
On the skid.
We got five minutes max.
What happens in five minutes?
It's no big deal. Just engine failure.
Good thing I only need three.
- Oh, thank God.
- No, no! Natalie, do not...
Oh, my God! Get me out of here.
I need you to stay still.
I have to stabilize the car.
Hurry, please.
Car secured.
Got it.
What the hell?
Shit.
Dylan! Oh, my God. Are you all right?
Jesus. Joby's pinned!
Ugh. Goddamn it.
Joby, I'm coming down.
Harrison, you're flying.
Marcus, rig me a rope.
- Handing over.
- Taking over.
- Be ready to cut.
- Roger that.
Hooked up.
Out the door.
Ray's clear.
Natalie, don't you worry.
I'm gonna get you out...
This thing isn't gonna hold!
Ray, we are in the red!
We are going to crash!
Natalie, we are going now!
I got you!
- Cut it!
- Joby, swing!
Yeah!
What do we say we get you home now?
I think that's a really good idea.
Now, the Sendai quake
in Japan was considered...
...one of the five strongest since 1900.
It was so powerful, in fact...
...that it moved the main island
of Japan eight feet.
This is just one
of the 1.3 million earthquakes...
...that occur around the globe
each year.
The largest ever recorded here
in North America:
Anchorage, Alaska, 1964. A 9.1.
The earth shook for five straight minutes.
The energy release was the equivalent
of 10 million atom bombs...
...the size of the one
dropped on Hiroshima.
And that's not the biggest earthquake
ever recorded.
No, the biggest was four years earlier off
the coast of Valdivia in Southern Chile.
A 9.5 on the Richter scale.
Right there.
Bam.
This quake lasted 11 minutes
and spawned a tsunami 82 feet high...
...that leveled Hilo, Hawaii
8000 miles away.
So, um...
It's mass destruction like this...
...that shows just how important
the research that we're doing here is...
...because we need to be able
to predict these things. Right?
To plan and prepare for them.
Yes, ma'am.
Professor, do you think something
that intense could happen here?
Well, the San Andreas fault
runs right up the spine of California.
It's the demarcation line between two
tectonic plates that are constantly moving.
And add to that the fact that
it's supposed to happen every 150 years...
...and we're about 100 years overdue...
...I'd say it's not a matter of if...
...it's a matter of when.
Damn, Godzilla.
What the hell'd you do to her this time?
Played a little tug of war with a car.
How soon before you get her fixed?
I'll call Martinez today.
Get a new one sent over to maintenance.
Elgin, you move any faster,
you're gonna break that hip.
Harrison said you're taking off
with Blake for a few days.
Yeah. Leaving tomorrow.
Driving her back up to school.
Volleyball team has their first game
this weekend.
I figure we cruise up the coast.
Do a little camping.
Dude, I can't believe
she's in college already.
I know.
- Too fast, brother. I'll catch you inside.
- All right, man.
- Lawrence, I gotta show you something.
- Yeah?
Aha!
Now, we got a rare low-level
seismic swarm out in Falco, Nevada.
23 small quakes, all tiny.
2.0 to 2.6 in the last 24 hours.
Where the hell is Falco, Nevada?
35 miles southeast of Vegas,
maybe 5 miles from the Hoover Dam.
All right.
There aren't any faults out there.
Any known faults. Now, if we get there
while the mini quakes continue...
...we can test our theory.
And if the magnetic pulse rate
goes up before the quakes...
- Then we're predicting them.
- Then we are predicting them.
All right.
Let's go check it out.
- Hi, Dad.
- Hey, sweetie.
I was wondering if there was room
for my bike.
Thought that I could ride it to class,
then I wouldn't have to buy a parking pass.
That's a great idea. I'm sure
I could figure out a way to fit it in.
All right, great. I can't find the key
to the lock at Mom's...
...so it's either in the top left drawer
of my dresser...
...or on top of the wardrobe
in my pink shoe box.
Okay, no problem. I'll find it.
I don't know if you have plans,
but I would love to take you to dinner.
You could even invite your mom along.
It'd be fun.
Oh, thanks, Dad.
But we already have plans with Daniel.
Dad?
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, of course I am.
Totally cool. No problem at all.
Okay. I'll see you tomorrow, then.
Okay.
And don't forget the bike key.
I won't. I got it.
Bye, Dad. I love you.
I love you, too, honey.
Bye.
Come here, you guys.
Let's take a picture.
Come on, Dad!
Lawrence, it's incredible.
This is the third mini quake
since we've been here.
And the magnetic pulse rate
has increased before each one of them.
We got a pattern, my friend.
That was a 2.2.
Our model's predictive.
We got it right, man! Finally!
Yep, we sure did. Ha, ha.
Oh, shit.
What's wrong?
Pulse rates are spiking again.
They're huge.
Are you serious?
Kim?
We're about to have a major quake.
It jumped to a 7.1!
Jesus, Kim!
Get the hell outta there!
Everybody get off the dam!
Move! Now! Now!
Everybody off! Hurry up!
Stay behind the barriers!
Come on, move!
Kim! Hurry!
Come here! I got you.
Oh, my God! Please! Oh, my God!
Kim! Hurry up!
Lawrence!
- Kim!
- No! No!
Close your eyes.
Oh, God!
Are you okay?
The southern part of Nevada...
...was rocked today
by what seismologists are calling...
...the most destructive earthquake
ever recorded in that area.
Officials are saying that Hoover Dam
is a total loss.
Lake Havasu City, Needles, Blythe
and Laughlin also suffered major damage.
Additional support from Los Angeles,
including L.A.F.D. air rescue...
...is expected to begin arriving
in the next 24 hours.
Hi, Dad.
- Hey, honey.
- We just saw the news.
I know. I'm so sorry.
We're heading out tomorrow.
No, I get it. This one's really bad, Dad.
Yeah, this one's tough.
Earthquakes can rise and fall
in intensity during their duration...
- Hey, Em.
- Hey.
- Good to see you.
- You, too.
Ah, Daniel.
Ray. Good to finally meet you.
It's good to meet you, too.
Heck of a place you got here, man.
- Thank you.
- Welcome.
So, Dad is heading to Nevada tomorrow.
Oh, it's terrible what happened.
Please be safe over there, okay?
Yeah, we will. And I promise
I'm gonna make it up to you, honey.
Dad, it's really no problem.
The drive is not that bad.
Wait, why don't I take you up there.
I'm flying to San Francisco.
We can head to Seattle right after.
Give me an opportunity to catch
a volleyball game.
That's a good idea.
And it'll give your mom a chance to get all
her stuff moved in without me in the way.
Right.
You guys moving in?
Yeah. I was meaning to tell you,
but we haven't had a chance to...
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Thanks.
That's great.
Call me when you get there.
- I will.
- All right.
I love you, Dad.
You be careful, please.
I will, I will. I love you, too.
I'll get her bike.
I'm sorry you guys
can't go up there together.
Yep. Me, too.
Ray.
I was gonna tell you.
We just decided to do it.
Don't worry about it.
Hey, if you want...
I'll get those papers signed for you, too.
It was a Sunday afternoon.
Obviously, people weren't at work.
They weren't asleep.
Even so, we know the devastation
was fairly...
- This is bad.
- Yeah.
What time we heading out?
14:30. Guys are prepping the gear now.
All right. Let's get to work.
--it's a fairly sophisticated
rescue operation underway.
So this Daniel guy's taking Blake now?
I would have just called in sick.
It's why I'm the boss and you're not.
Pretty sure we can manage
a few days without ya.
Shoe's untied.
Are you kidding me?
Blake.
I want you to know that I respect
what you and your dad have.
And I know that your mom moving in
has to feel like a pretty big step.
But I'm never gonna try to change
what you have with him...
...or take his place.
Okay?
Yeah.
Okay, cool.
Hey, how come you never had kids?
Oh, I did.
This is one of them right here.
She's a nice addition to
the San Francisco skyline, don't you think?
"The Gate."
Catchy. right?
Yeah, I like it.
Mom was telling me about this. She said
it's the tallest building in the city, right?
When it's finished,
it'll be the tallest, strongest...
...and it's already 80 percent sold.
But honestly...
...I guess I never had any kids
because I was always so busy raising these.
Mom texted. She's having lunch
with your sister today.
Yeah, she's only in town for a few days
and really wanted to meet her.
I'm a little nervous though.
Susan can be kind of overprotective.
Thank you.
Jonathan.
- Good morning, Mr. Riddick.
- Morning.
Gonna be okay, Blake?
Yeah, I'll be fine.
Hi.
Hello.
I'm sorry, Lawrence.
- Can I get you anything?
- No. I'm fine, Alexi. Thank you.
Are you sure you want to be here?
I can use the distraction, actually.
Yeah?
There's a reporter outside.
Says she's doing a segment
on what happened in Nevada.
I'm gonna tell her
that it's not a good time.
No, wait a minute.
Kim gave his life for this.
People need to know
that we can predict these things now.
You want a copy?
I got about a thousand in storage.
No one listens to us
until the ground shakes, I guess.
They told me
what happened to your colleague.
We don't have to do this now.
Yeah, we do.
We're good to go.
Okay.
Rolling.
First question:
How come no one saw what happened
in Nevada coming?
Because we didn't know
there were any fault lines out there.
Why not?
Heh.
Contrary to popular belief,
scientists don't know everything.
I understand that you publicly stated...
...that, someday, scientists
will be able to predict earthquakes.
Well, actually, as of yesterday,
we now believe that we can predict them.
Professor!
Talk to you a sec?
Yeah. I'm sorry. Excuse me.
What is it?
Current pulse rates at our monitoring
stations. All along the San Andreas fault.
Their averages are spiking
from 82 to 85...
...with the biggest jumps
coming from San Francisco.
More than 20 points higher
than what we saw in Nevada.
There's no way.
We checked. We double-checked.
Then we reset all the instruments
and triple-checked. Those are the counts.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
Um...
Okay, uh...
If, uh...
If we draw a line...
...from the bottom of the San Andreas
up to the Hoover Dam...
...it almost literally follows
the Colorado River...
...which is a natural deformation event.
And geologically...
...deformation events mark boundaries.
They mark boundaries.
So, what if...?
What if this...
...whole chunk of land
is connected to our tectonic plate?
That would tell us that what happened
yesterday in Nevada was not an anomaly.
No.
What if it was a precursor movement...
...along the leading edge
of the plate boundary fault...
...from Los Angeles
all the way up to San Francisco?
Are you saying you think
the whole San Andreas fault might go off?
Yes, that's exactly what I'm saying.
Who should we call?
Everybody.
Mm.
Oh, bloody hell.
I have something. Here.
I'm a complete idiot.
No.
Thank you very much. That's very kind.
Yeah, no problem.
I'm Blake, by the way.
Oh, yeah. I'm Blake. I'm not Blake!
I'm Ben. Ben Taylor is my name.
Pleased to meet you.
It's nice to meet you.
So was that your father
you came in with?
Daniel Riddick?
Um, he's my mom's boyfriend.
- Ah.
- Are you meeting with him?
Oh, no. I...
Pfft. Not even close.
I wish.
I'm interviewing for a job here...
...and Mr. Riddick
is the boss of the boss...
- ...of the boss that I'd be working for.
- Heh.
So, what kind of job
are you interviewing for?
Anything in engineering or design.
I'm not picky or proud.
I just want to work here.
If you're an architect,
this is the place to be.
Hi. I'm Ollie. He's my brother.
Hi. It's nice to meet you, Ollie.
I'm Blake.
You know, you're quite beautiful.
- Why, thank you.
- Ollie. Do you...?
Sorry.
Do you remember what we discussed?
Sit still and no talking.
It's not normal to bring little brothers
to job interviews.
And let's not embarrass me, okay?
Do you mind if I get your phone number
for him?
Ollie!
- It's exactly...
- What?
You'll never ask for it. And then I'll have to
listen to how much you regretted not getting it.
- Heh.
- Mr. Taylor?
- Ms. Carter will see you now.
- Thank you.
I, uh...
Good luck.
Thank you. And, you, sit here
and don't say another word.
- Hi. I'm Ben.
- Hello.
- We're gonna head straight over.
- Excellent.
What do you want to talk about?
Um...
- Where you from?
- England.
Ben thought while our parents
were gonna be on a cruise...
...he and I should take a holiday here
in the city, after his interview.
- Awesome.
- Oh.
Would you like to hear our itinerary?
Susan. It's nice to finally meet you.
You as well.
Now that Daniel's asked you to move in
with him, things must be pretty serious.
Yes.
Hi. I'm Larissa.
I'll be taking care of you today.
Can I tell you about our specials?
Please, I'd love to hear...
Actually, could you come back
in a few minutes, Larissa?
Yeah. Sure.
So, I understand
you've been married before?
Yes.
- And you have just the one daughter. Right?
- Right.
Your other one drowned in an accident?
Yes, to put it bluntly.
Oh, I didn't mean it like that.
Can you just give me one minute?
Hi. Everything okay?
Yeah. Uh...
Oh, I'm on my way to maintenance
before we head out and...
Am I interrupting anything?
Nothing important. What's going on?
Look, I just wanted to tell you
I was sorry for how I acted yesterday.
No, Ray, really.
No, Emma.
I just wasn't ready to hear about you
and Blake moving in with someone else.
I should've told you before.
- Hey, how's Blake feel about it?
- You know.
She'd like us to be a family again.
I think it's gonna be hard for her to...
Emma.
Oh, my God.
We're having an earthquake.
Oh, Jesus, Ray.
I gotta get outta here.
- Where are you?
- Aah! Um...
The Tate Weston.
Shit, you're on the top floor.
Emma, listen:
Get as many people
as you can to the roof.
- I'm in the helo and I'll get you from there.
- Okay, okay!
Get to the roof, honey.
No, no, no!
Under the table.
Drop, cover and hold on!
Lawrence, the Richter just jumped
from a 6.5 to an 8.5.
What does that mean?
Powers of ten!
So it's a hundred times stronger now!
Don't worry. Caltech is probably
the safest place to be right now.
Professor! It looks like the whole
San Andreas fault line is being activated.
And it's heading toward San Francisco.
All right. All done.
Okay.
Well, it was really nice to meet you, Ollie.
I hope you have fun while you're here.
Bye, Blake. It was nice meeting you,
as well.
Goodbye.
Oh, and, um...
I almost forgot. Do you mind if I
borrow your book for a second?
Tell Ben that I'll put in a good word
for him.
Heh.
- Bye.
I can't wait to be 20.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
It's an earthquake!
Well, go, go, go! Get us outta here!
God.
Go, man! Hurry, hurry!
The exit! Go, go, go!
Jesus Christ!
Oh, shit! Go!
My legs!
You okay?
Oh, my God. He's dead!
Blake?
- Blake? Blake.
- He's dead.
Are you okay?
Are you hurt?
No, I don't think...
I don't think so.
But my legs are stuck.
Please.
Come on. Okay. Okay.
We're gonna get you out of here. Okay?
On, God. Okay.
Think.
Daniel?
- Blake, I'm gonna go for help.
- No, Daniel...
- I'll be right back. I'll be right back.
- No, Daniel. Don't.
Don't leave me alone!
Daniel!
Daniel.
Let's go! Keep moving!
- Come on. Hurry!
- Help!
- Let's go!
- Keep moving! Keep moving! Let's go!
- Help!
There's a girl trapped in a town car!
- Where?
- In the parking garage!
Oh, God!
Allen!
Get up! Get up!
Help me, somebody! Help me, please!
Out the building! Get outside!
Get out in the open! Hurry!
Mr. Riddick!
Mr. Riddick?
I need air.
Mr. Riddick!
Help me!
Move it!
Blake.
Oh, my God.
- Susan!
- Emma!
Susan! We gotta get to the roof!
We've gotta get out of here!
- This way!
- You can't...
Get out of my way!
Susan! Susan!
Aah! Unh.
Aah! Oh, my God.
There's the exit!
This way! Get over here!
Ma'am! We gotta go!
Okay. Okay.
Come on! Keep moving! Keep moving!
Larissa! Larissa,
you have to come with me!
We've gotta get to the roof!
Everybody!
There's a rescue helicopter coming!
- No! Wait!
- Wait! We've gotta go up!
- Oh, God!
- Oh, my God!
Come on!
This way! This way!
Oh, my God.
Ray, you better be right about this.
Aah! Ugh!
Ray.
Phew.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Uh...
Up there!
Aah!
Ugh!
Oh, shit.
Come on, Emma. Come on. We gotta go.
Emma, run!
Aah!
Emma.
Ray!
Emma!
I got you!
Ray.
Emma, are you hurt?
- Um...
- Are you hurt?
I don't think so.
Okay. It's gonna be okay, but listen.
We gotta get outta here.
Get to the front left seat. I'll be there.
- Okay
- Okay?
Shit!
Oh, my God.
Get up!
Oh, God.
- Ray!
- Hold on!
Help!
Somebody help me!
Help! Somebody help!
This is Ray.
- Dad, please help!
- Blake, what's wrong?
There's been a huge earthquake!
I don't know where Daniel went.
I'm stuck in a limo in a garage in the dark.
I'm really, really scared, Dad!
Baby, are you hurt?
No, but my leg is...
Blake! Goddamn it.
What? What is it?
Shit.
Her cell service just went out.
There's no way rescue personnel are
gonna be digging in garages any time soon.
There's too many populated places
above ground.
What, uh...?
What are we gonna do?
We're going to get our daughter.
Blake!
- Blake!
- Help! I'm over here!
Blake! Blake, it's Ben. Are you okay?
I can't get out. The roof's collapsing.
My legs are trapped.
Okay. Okay.
All right, Ollie, we need to lift this beam
to get the pressure off her legs.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
Oh, let's try this.
Okay, ready?
Ready? One, two, three.
Come on, Ollie.
Give it everything you've got.
I am!
It's not working!
Ollie!
Ben?
- Ollie?
- We're still here.
We're still here.
Oh, no.
No.
You have to get out of here.
This building's gonna collapse.
There's not a chance in hell
we're leaving you in there.
Okay. Okay.
All right.
Here we go.
Okay.
Brilliant. It's working!
All right.
It won't go any higher.
I'm still stuck!
- Ollie!
- She's moving!
Hurry, hurry. Hurry!
Got you!
Are you okay?
Yeah.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
Thank you. Thank you, guys.
Pleasure.
Good job.
Come on. It's another aftershock.
We've got to get out of here.
- Look out!
- Move, move, move! Hurry!
Come on! Come on! We have to
get away from these buildings.
Blake!
- Oh, my God.
- Blake! This way!
This way!
Jesus!
- Oh, my God!
- Ollie!
Blake!
Come on!
Go, go, go!
All right, this way.
I cannot believe that Daniel
just took off.
What an asshole.
Step aside.
I gotta get ahold of my parents.
I gotta let them know I'm okay.
Cell phones aren't working. I've tried.
We need to find an electronics store.
Does that book of yours list businesses?
My book has everything.
The good news is most of
our emergency systems are still working.
We've got signals coming in
from 17 monitors.
We just experienced a 9.1.
Lawrence. You need to see this.
What do we got?
Here are the pulse rates
before the quake.
Yeah, okay.
And here are the pulse rates now.
The same. Or higher.
So the earthquake didn't diminish them.
Oh, man.
Oh, this is not good.
Alexi, I want all the data from every monitoring
station still up along the fault line.
- And get it for me now.
- Right.
- What's going on?
- This is not over.
Shit.
Oh, man. This thing's fried.
Come on. I need everybody.
- What are we doing?
- Getting you on the air. To warn people.
- How? There's no way to upload a signal.
- Oh.
You're at Caltech.
Okay, who wants an "A" in independent
study? I'm starting a new class:
"How to Save Lives
by Hacking Media Outlets."
Hell, yeah, man. I'm in.
Sweet. Get your laptop. Let's go.
Right here. Move, move, move.
Here we go. Up. Lift.
Let's go! Over here.
It should be just up ahead.
There it is.
Okay, anything running on electricity
isn't gonna work...
...so we have to find
a rotary or a push-button phone.
How do you know all this?
My dad.
He works for L.A. Fire and Rescue.
Over here.
Great. I'll look for a landline.
I got one!
Blake?
Dad.
Dad. I got out. I'm okay.
Aah. She's okay.
Oh.
Let me talk to her.
Blake?
Mom?
Oh, thank God, honey.
Is Daniel okay?
He left me, Mom.
He what?
He told a security guard where I was...
...and then he just took off...
...and these two brothers that I met
overheard him and they came to help me.
I'm with them right now.
He left her?
We're coming to get you, honey.
Where are you?
I'm in an electronics store in Chinatown.
Honey, it's gonna be okay,
but I need you to listen to me.
Getting outta there is gonna be
a complete gridlock nightmare.
So get to higher ground. It's safer.
That's where I'm gonna
be able to see you.
Do you remember where we spent
Mallory's birthday weekend?
- At Coit Tower?
- Yeah. Yeah.
- That tall cement nozzle thing on the hill.
- Exactly.
Don't stop anywhere. Go there.
That's where we'll meet.
Stay strong, honey.
- We're coming to get you.
- Okay.
Wait, Mom.
How are you and Dad together?
We'll explain later. Okay, honey?
I love you.
I love you guys.
Bye.
Hi, you've reached Daniel. Please
leave me a message and I'll get back to you.
You left my daughter?
If you're not already dead,
I'm gonna fucking kill you.
Thattagirl.
All right. We need to get going.
So how is your dad going to pick us up?
He's on his way in a helicopter.
That's so cool.
I need you to look up Coit Tower
on your map.
It's your turn.
Your parents will be worried sick.
Thank you.
Don't run.
Get in the street.
Where are we going?
- Stay away from the buildings.
- He wasn't there.
- Another aftershock!
- It's okay. It's all right.
Run! Run!
Get out of my way!
Hey! That was my spot!
You know, when you were
talking to Blake...
...that was the first time I heard you
say Mallory's name since we lost her.
Hey, did you know that Blake keeps
pictures from our San Francisco trip?
Yeah, in her memory box.
It's ironic.
Us heading back up there.
It was a fun trip.
- Where are we?
- Bakersfield.
Or what's left of it.
We're just about 90 minutes
from San Francisco.
Uh...
Ray?
Did you just turn off the engine?
We got a gearbox failure.
Must've been that hit we took in L.A.
- I'm gonna have to autorotate down.
- Auto-what?
We're gonna crash.
- Right. Okay.
- Hold on.
Here we go.
Aah!
Hold on!
- Oh, my God!
- Almost there. Almost there.
We're just gonna set her down
right here.
Jesus!
Oh, my God!
We got fuel all over us.
We need to get outta here.
Get off me!
- Come on, we gotta go. Stay low. Stay low.
- Okay.
It's okay. We just gotta keep moving.
Just gotta keep moving.
- Give it to me.
- Stay here, man!
No, it's mine!
I got the last one here, Robin!
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
Get in, get in, get in, get in.
Looks like it's been stolen.
All right. Well, we'll steal it again.
Ray.
Easy.
Back it up! Come on!
I'll be needing that truck.
Not today.
Oh, my God.
The quake centered about 20
miles east of downtown Los Angeles.
Cell towers are down.
Most of the city's electricity, down.
Communication at a virtual standstill.
The devastation to Southern California
is expected to be massive.
In fact, the entire state will take a hit. We're
already getting reports of collapsed buildings...
We're in.
- Yes!
- Mm.
...as far north
as San Francisco and the Bay Area.
There have been
at least five aftershocks ranging...
Okay. Here we go.
Producers are telling us we have
our first live feed from Los Angeles.
Serena Johnson is on the ground
at the seismology center at Caltech.
Hello, Chris.
I'm here with Dr. Lawrence Hayes, Executive
Director for Earthquake Studies at Caltech.
He and his research partner,
Dr. Kim Park...
...have come up with a model
that predicts earthquakes.
They knew L.A. was going to get hit.
But nobody listened to them.
It's time now to listen.
- Go ahead, doctor.
- Okay.
In seismology terms, what we're
experiencing is what we call a swarm event.
Basically, California's entire
tectonic plate has shifted.
The quake we experienced in Los Angeles
did damage all the way up in San Francisco.
Yeah, but the earthquake that they felt
was from movement along the fault line...
...in the Central Valley.
Their end of the fault line
has not moved yet.
More importantly, people need to know
that the shaking is not over.
And it's not aftershocks I'm talking about.
San Francisco will get hit again.
And it's going to be a bigger monster
this time.
Our models are predicting
a 9.5 or greater.
It will be so big that, even though
it's happening here in California...
...you will feel it on the East Coast.
Now, I cannot emphasize this enough
to the people of San Francisco:
You need to get out. And I mean now.
And, if you can't, you need to find
any means possible...
...to drop, cover and hold on.
Because your life is gonna depend on it.
God be with you.
Aftershocks continue to rock
the Los Angeles area.
You ever think about what our life
would be like if we hadn't lost Mallory?
- Em, don't.
- I do.
All the time.
We moved on.
No, we didn't move on.
We stopped moving.
You didn't lose her on your watch.
- No. But I lost her.
- Can we not talk about this?
You owe it to me.
This! This is the most
I've gotten out of you since she died.
I need to know, Ray.
Was it me?
What did I do?
- I never blamed you.
- I don't wanna talk about it.
It doesn't matter.
She's gone. Now you're gone...
What's the point?
I guess the point is...
...this is why I didn't stick around.
Hey! Hey!
- Look out! Watch out! You have to stop!
- Hey! Slow down! Hey!
- Ray!
- Aah!
What is this?
The San Andreas fault.
I told you
we should've gone the other way.
Because you knew
this was gonna happen?
Oh. You!
- We owe you guys a huge thanks.
- Really.
No need.
We nearly made
the same mistake ourselves...
...but busted an axle
when we went off the road.
Thank goodness my eyes
are better than his.
Heh. Do you know
if there's any way around this?
Well...
...the 198 might not be out.
- Through the pass.
- How far is that?
Oh, ya gotta backtrack,
maybe, 70 miles or so.
Sir, if you don't mind me asking...
...where'd you get your hat?
You guys really bailed us out.
You sure we can't fly you anywhere?
Yeah. Our son lives in the mountains.
There's no place to land.
- Thanks for the wheels.
- You bet.
Be safe.
Bye.
We should be fueled up
in a couple of minutes.
Okay. Great.
Everything okay?
You asked me before if it was you.
It wasn't.
I knew you didn't blame me.
I just didn't know how to deal
with Mallory's death.
It was my idea
to take Mallory rafting that day.
Ray.
You can't blame yourself
for what happened.
It's just different when it's your own kid.
I know.
Sometimes I can't get that look she had
outta my head.
The moment she realized...
...that I wasn't gonna be able to save her.
And then coming home every day
to you and Blake only made it harder.
Because nothing was the way it used
to be. And the way it used to be was...
It was perfect.
I should've let you in.
I just didn't know how.
I'm so sorry for how things
ended with us, Em.
I really am.
If you couldn't save our daughter...
...then nobody could have.
I miss her so much.
Me, too.
Let's go get our daughter.
Let's go! Keep it moving! Let's go!
Come on. Let's go.
Follow the evacuation route.
Just a few more blocks
to Lombard Avenue...
...which leads to Coit Tower.
Do you mind if I ask why you wear
two of the same necklaces?
Um...
One of them used to be my sister's.
I started wearing it after she died.
We had given them to each other
for Christmas the year before.
- I'm so sorry. I didn't mean...
- No. It's okay.
I'm not hiding them.
Hey. Check it out.
What are you doing?
They should have a supply box.
It'll have stuff that we can use.
Is this it?
Yes!
Oh, okay.
Here we go.
Every city has a tactical channel...
...first responders use to communicate on.
We can listen in,
we can see what's going on.
Okay.
- Here. Take these.
- Yeah.
- Take this.
- What's an MRE?
Meals Ready-to-Eat.
These things have a shelf life
of over three years.
- Wow.
- They don't taste so good.
Blake!
I think we're going to have a problem with
that big nozzle thing you were talking about.
What?
What do you mean?
Oh, my God.
We have to go to Plan B.
I didn't think we had one.
We do now.
We need to get to the next highest ground
so that we can signal my dad in the helicopter.
That would be Nob Hill.
It's the highest point in the city.
It's the other way.
- Okay. Come on!
- No.
Blake, wait! Wait! Just...
Just wait.
Coming through. Move, move, move!
Blake, we'd be the only ones
going that way.
My dad said to get to higher ground,
so that's what we gotta do.
But...
What if he doesn't make it?
Listen, I know that this sounds crazy.
But you have to trust me that he will.
I... I ca...
Ben.
Did you know about the push-button
phone working with the landline?
The supply box?
Tactical radio channels?
I really think we should stick with her.
Okay.
Looks like we're going to Nob Hill.
Let's go.
The following message
is transmitted at the request...
...of the California Emergency Management.
Residents are encouraged
to evacuate immediately.
Looks like the whole city's evacuating.
Em, we got a problem at the airport.
Where are we gonna land?
We can't. At least, not in the city.
Come with me.
Uh...
Okay.
You gotta be kidding me.
Em, we have no place
to set this plane down...
...and we have to get as close
to Coit Tower as we possibly can.
In three minutes,
we're gonna be over Embarcadero.
And?
And, we're gonna drop into AT&T Park.
- But I don't know how to parachute.
- That's okay. We're gonna tandem-jump.
I think we should stay with the plane.
The plane's gonna nosedive in the Pacific
as soon as it runs out of gas.
Okay.
Hmm.
Trust me.
Oh, my God!
You ready?
Do I sound ready?
Yep!
It's been a while
since I got you to second base.
With a grave warning from Dr. Lawrence
Hayes blanketing the airwaves...
...San Francisco has begun evacuation.
The Coast Guard is asking anyone
with access to a boat to please volunteer.
...the fault line in the Central Valley.
Their end of the fault line
has not moved yet.
San Francisco is going to get hit again,
and this will be a much bigger monster.
I hope we've given everyone
enough warning.
This is it, isn't it?
Right now, I wanna be so wrong.
Everyone, take cover!
This will be over soon here.
But pray for the people
of San Francisco.
Did you know "Nob" is a slang term...
..."which means 'rich or wealthy.'
It's a shortened version of the word 'nobility, '
because of the families that live there.
It's also derisively known as 'Snob Hill."'
What is it?
Daniel built that building.
Oh, my God!
Oh, shit.
Move! Move!
Come on, Ollie!
Ugh!
Ollie!
I want to go home now!
Just hold on!
It's gonna be okay. I promise!
Head to the building!
They're gonna get killed out there.
Em, get to the side of the stadium.
I'll be right there.
I'll be right there!
It's not safe here. Go to the side
of the stadium, right now!
This building's gonna collapse.
You need to move!
Come on. Go, go.
Hurry! You gotta get off the street!
Get to the side of the stadium!
Right now! Side of the stadium!
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Off the street! Get to the stadium.
Side of the stadium! Come on!
Get out of the street!
Help!
It's all right. Come on. I got you.
I got you. And up!
Go.
Over here, Ray!
- I got her! I got her.
- Here, take her, Em.
You're gonna be okay.
You're gonna be okay. It's all right.
Everybody down!
- Everybody okay?
- We're good.
Anybody hurt?
No.
Emma.
You okay?
Yeah.
How'd you know we'd be safe'?
Just get up against something sturdy.
Protect yourself.
Triangle of life.
Let's go.
She's gonna be okay.
But how do we get through that?
We don't.
We go around it.
Ugh. Okay.
Okay.
We have to get that out of there.
If you try walking with it,
it could cause more damage.
This is gonna hurt.
Are you ready?
Okay.
Ben!
I'm all right.
Do you think you could
put some weight on it?
We have to keep moving.
We gotta get up that hill.
Yeah.
Okay.
Here.
How bad did they get hit?
9.6.
Largest quake in recorded history.
Oh, no.
Coit's been burning a while.
She's gone someplace else.
Now, where are you, baby?
Where are you?
What's your Plan B?
Oh, shit.
What's happening?
We gotta go. Water being pulled out
like that's a tsunami.
We gotta get outta the bay, now.
Wait. Wait, wait a second.
Just give me one second.
God!
The Weather Service
has issued a tsunami warning...
...for coastal areas of Northern and Central
California, including the following counties:
Marin, Napa, San Francisco
and Monterey.
Come on, guys. We gotta go!
We gotta go! We gotta move fast!
We gotta get to Daniel's building.
Ray.
I see it!
All right, hold on!
We gotta get over it before it crests!
Come on!
We're gonna make it.
- We're gonna make it!
- Yeah.
- Oh, Shit!
- Aah!
Ray!
Move it!
Out of my way!
Shit.
What's that noise?
We're not high enough.
Get down! Get down! Take cover!
Hold on tight, Ollie!
Ben!
Ollie.
The water's still rising.
We have to get higher.
This way!
Ben.
Ollie, come. Grab on.
I've got you.
Oh, my God.
Where is she, Ray?
She's a smart girl.
She'd know to head
for one of these high-rises.
- Hmm.
- We just gotta find her.
- Ugh.
- Are you all right?
We need to take a look at that leg.
Okay.
Ollie, see if there's something
that we can use as a bandage.
- And see if you can find clean water.
- Yeah.
Okay.
Okay. Let's see
what we're dealing with here.
What?
You're absolutely...
You're unbelievable.
Mum's going to love her.
There are a few towels in here.
Oh, great.
I'll look for some water.
Heh.
Just jump! Come on!
I got you.
Hey!
I can see some people in a boat!
No way.
No way!
Those are my parents!
Mom! Dad! Mom!
- Help! Hey!
- Dad!
Dad! Mom!
Mom.
They can't hear us.
What?
Em, if we don't get to her soon,
we're gonna need some gas.
We got maybe an hour and a half, tops
before...
- Ray.
- Yeah?
Hold on.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God, it's Blake!
Oh, my God!
Emma! Oh, we found her.
Blake!
Help! Blake!
Ollie!
I've got you! I've got you!
Where's Blake?
She's back there!
Stay here, Ollie.
Blake!
Bla...
No! No!
No!
The building's sinking!
We have to move.
We have to move up.
Come on, Ollie, hurry!
No, no, no.
No! Oh, my God, Blake!
Em, take the wheel.
I see a way in. I'm going after her.
Ray!
I'm bringing her back.
I promise.
- Blake!
- Daddy!
The door's blocked!
Blake, don't worry.
I'm gonna get you outta here.
Okay? I'm getting you out!
Daddy, I'm scared.
I'm running out of air!
Daddy, I don't think I can do this.
Blake, you hold on, hold on!
There!
Ben, I don't want Blake to die.
She's not going to die.
I'm going back for her.
Okay? But I need you to stay here.
Okay?
Good boy.
Ollie!
Ben!
On my back! On my back, Ollie!
Blake's going to die.
Isn't she?
All right.
Dad.
I love...
I love you, Dad.
And please tell...
Please tell Mom that I love her, too.
Blake, don't you quit on me!
- Blake!
- I'm sorry, Dad.
Blake!
No!
Blake! Oh, my God!
Move, Ollie. Move.
Come on. Breathe, Blake.
Breathe, honey.
We gotta get outta here.
Break a window!
Oh, my God.
Move! Get outta the way!
Watch out!
Get on! Let's go! Let's go!
Move. Move, Ollie, move.
Come on, Ray.
- Take her, Emma.
- I got her.
It's okay. Here you go.
Wake up, honey.
Come on.
Okay, we got her.
Get us outta here, Em!
The building's coming down.
Everybody down!
Okay, Blake.
Your dad and I, we're right here now.
We're right here.
Breathe, Blake. Breathe.
- Come on. Breathe.
- Don't leave me.
Dad and I are right here, all right?
Okay.
Ray...
My baby.
I'm not gonna lose you, too. No.
Come on.
Oh, my God.
Okay. Okay.
- Mom.
- I'm right here. I'm right here. Yeah.
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
We are now getting a better
picture of the scale of the devastation.
And this was the sight
in many neighborhoods:
Families and friends
huddled together...
...shaken but grateful to still be alive.
Seismologists will be keeping a close watch
on all of the world's tectonic plates...
...as the San Andreas quake could have
rippling effects throughout the globe.
Closer to home,
nerves are finally calming.
Hey.
You did good.
Thank you.
We all did.
Authorities in San Francisco are attributing
a tremendous amount of lives saved...
...thanks to local experts, who were able
to give ample warning of the massive quake.
Meanwhile, recovery efforts
have begun in the Bay Area...
...where FEMA, the National Guard
and U.N. relief teams...
...have all been mobilized...
...aided by the thousands of volunteers
pouring into the state.
Our Father, who art in Heaven,
hallowed by thy name.
Ollie. Ben.
I, uh...
I found this on the boat.
Thank you.
I wanna thank you guys
for being there for Blake.
Yeah, thank you.
You're welcome.
But it was more like
she was there for us.
I think.
This is incredible.
So...
...what now?
Now we rebuild.